特别重要的一元操作被称为阈值处理。
A particularly important monadic operation is referred to as thresholding.
考虑这里的两个图像。第一个是灰度图像和第二个图像
Consider the two images here. The first one is a grey scale image and the second image
你可以看到更加鲜明的对比;实际上，像素只有两个值-它们
you can see is much more contrasty; in fact, the pixels have only got two values—they
是黑色还是白色。现在我们在这里所做的是合乎逻辑的
are either black or white. Now what we have done here is made a logical
决定每个输入值。如果输入值小于阈值，则参考
decision on every input value. If the input value is less than the threshold, referred
通过符号T，结果是假的，我们通过黑色像素表示
to by the symbol T, then the result is false and we represent that by a black pixel in
输出图像。如果输入像素大于等于
the output image. If the input pixel is greater than and equal
到T，然后我们说结果为真，结果像素显示为白色。
to T, then we say the result is true and the resulting pixel is displayed as white.
如果我们以图形方式显示此函数，我们可以看到它非常非常非线性。
If we display this function graphically, we can see that it is very, very non-linear.
输出为0直到达到T的输入值，然后输出值变为真。
The output is 0 up until we reach the input value of T, and then the output value becomes true.
在MATLAB中我们显示一个像素值
In MATLAB when we display a pixel value that
有一个false值，它显示为黑色，当我们显示一个有值的像素
has got a value of false, it shows as black, and when we display a pixel that has a value
为true，显示为白色。MATLAB支持许多我们称之为逻辑的东西
of true it is displayed as white. MATLAB supports a number of what we call logical
运营商。这是比较两个数字量的方法。就在之前的例子中
operators. That is the way to compare two numeric quantities. Just in the example before
我们查看了>=运算符，我们也查看了<运算符。MATLAB有能力
we looked at the >= operator, and we also looked at the < operator. MATLAB has the ability
确定两个值是否相等;或不平等;比...更棒;少于;等等。
to determine whether two values are equal; or not equal; greater than; less than; and so on.
任何这些逻辑运算符的结果
The result of any of these logical operators
是一个逻辑价值;无论是真是假。现在MATLAB代表了真实的概念
is a logical value; it is either true or false. Now MATLAB represents the concepts of true
和false作为数值。True表示为1，false表示为0。
and false as numeric values. True is represented by 1 and false is represented by 0.
MATLAB还有一些内置的特殊常量，它们的名称为true和false。
MATLAB also has some special constants that are built in, and they have got the names true and false.
让我们从一些非常简单的事情开始。
Let’s start with something really simple.
我们会问“2大于1？”这个问题，我们知道这个结果
We will ask the question ‘is 2 greater than 1?’, and we know that the outcome of this
必须是真的。MATLAB给了我们一个值1.现在
must be true. And MATLAB has given us a value of 1. Now
我们将注意到我们在工作空间中创建了一个名为ans的​​新变量。Ans是自动的
we will note that we have created a new variable in the workspace called ans. Ans is an automatic
MATLAB用来保存最后一个操作或命令的结果的变量
variable that MATLAB uses to hold always the result of the last operation or command that
已经给出了。它是逻辑类型，这意味着它可以
has been given. It is of logical type, which means it can
只有真或假的值。所以我们得到了这个问题的答案
only have values of true or false. So the answer that we got to this question
是1，1是MATLAB用来表示true概念的数值。
is 1, and 1 is the numerical value that MATLAB uses to represent the concept of true.
同样，如果我们问的问题是“1大于2？”，我们就知道这一点
Similarly, if we ask the question ‘is 1 greater than 2?’, and we know that this
是假的，MATLAB返回的数值为0.这是MATLAB代表的方式
is false, MATLAB has returned as a numerical value of 0. It is how MATLAB represents the
虚假的概念。MATLAB有几个内置变量
concept of false. MATLAB has got a couple of built in variables
代表这些价值观。我们可以问它真实的价值。等效数值
to represent these values. We can ask it the value of true. The equivalent numerical value
是1.并且假，等效数值为0。
is 1. And false, the equivalent numerical value is 0.
我们也可以进行相等测试，所以我们可以说'1等于2？'。它不是;它
We can also do an equality test, so we can say ‘is 1 equal to 2?’. It is not; it
是假的。'2等于2吗？'是的，这是真的。
is false. ‘Is 2 equal to 2?’ Yes that is true.
当然，我们可以为变量分配逻辑测试，所以我可以说'a等于2
We can, of course, assign logical tests to variables, so I can say ‘a is equal to 2
等于3？'。我们在该工作空间中创建了一个名为a的新逻辑变量，它有一个值
equals 3?’. We created a new logical variable in that workspace called a, and it has a value
0，或假。之前我们研究过矢量化的概念
of 0, or false. Earlier we looked at the concept of vectorization
当我们在矩阵和标量之间进行算术运算时。逻辑运算符可以
when we perform arithmetic between a matrix and a scalar. Well the logical operators can
也可以以矢量化形式使用。在这种情况下发生的是逻辑测试完成
also be used in a vectorized form. What happens in this case is that the logical test is done
在输入矩阵中的每个元素和标量之间，结果是一个矩阵
between every element in the input matrix, and the scalar, and the result is a matrix
与输入矩阵的大小相同，其中每个元素都是逻辑值。该
with the same size as the input matrix in which every element is a logical value. The
输出矩阵中的元素为true或false。
elements in the output matrix are either true or false.
让我们展示一个具体的例子。我要创建一个矩阵m，它就要开始了
Let’s show a concrete example of this. I am going to create a matrix m and it is going
包含1到10之间的随机整数元素。矩阵将是4乘4。
to contain random integer elements between 1 and 10. The matrix is going to be 4 by 4.
我们有它。现在，如果我对此矩阵应用逻辑测试，
There we have it. Now if I apply a logical test to this matrix,
MATLAB要做的是将矩阵的每个元素与5进行比较。它正在进行中
what MATLAB is going to do is to compare every element of the matrix with 5. It is going
将>5测试应用于每个元素。所以我们可以在这个结果中看到：无论在哪里
to apply the >5 test to each element. And so what we can see in this result: wherever
有一个，这表示一个大于5的元素。
there are ones, this indicates an element that is greater than 5.
您还可以看到此结果是逻辑类型的矩阵;也就是说，每一个元素
You can also see that this result is a matrix of logical type; that is, every element in
此矩阵是一个逻辑值，只能是真或假，由数字表示
this matrix is a logical value which can only be true or false, represented by the numeric
值分别为1或0。我可以对这个矩阵应用相等测试
values 1 or 0 respectively. I can apply an equality test to this matrix
同样，我可以寻找所有相同的元素
as well, and I can look for all of the elements that are equal
我现在发现的是一个矩阵，其中两个表示元素
to 3. And what I find now is a matrix where the two ones indicate the elements of the
原始矩阵等于3.我们将继续前一个
original matrix that were equal to 3. We are going to follow on from a previous
例子，我们要做的是创建一个新变量;在这种情况下它会
example and what we are going to do is create a new variable; in this case it is going to
被称为b。我要做的是对图像中的每个像素应用逻辑测试
be called b. What I am going to do is to apply a logical test to every pixel in the image
即时通讯，这是你可以在上面看到的企鹅标志的形象。我要比较一下
im, which is the image of the penguin sign you can see above. And I am going to compare
所有这些像素值都是数值0.45，它将创建一个新变量
all of these pixel values to the numeric value 0.45, and it is going to create a new variable
在我的工作区中，我们可以看到它是逻辑类型。
in my workspace and we can see that it is of type logical.
我们看到它与原始图像im具有相同的尺寸。它有730行和1047列。
We see it has the same dimensions as the original image im. It has got 730 rows and 1047 columns.
它属于逻辑类型。此新矩阵中的每个元素都具有false值
It is of type logical. Each element in this new matrix has got a value of either false
或者是真的。现在让我们显示这个逻辑图像。
or true. Now let’s display this logical image.
我们走了，现在我们看到的是像素值非常清晰的图像;他们
Here we go, and what we see now is an image where the pixel values are quite crisp; they
是黑色还是白色。黑色值-我点击这里-得到的值为0，他们是
are either black or white. The black values — I click on here — have got a value of 0, they’re
假。这意味着他们没有通过测试-他们不到0.45。哪个像素
false. That means that they don’t pass the test — they are less than 0.45. Where a pixel
这里的值为1，它通过了测试-它大于0.45。
here has a value of 1, it does pass the test — it is greater than 0.45.
现在，您可能会问的问题是0.45的数量来自何处。好吧，我选择了
Now, the question you might ask is where does this number of 0.45 come from. Well I chose
它基于直方图，因为直方图非常清楚地表明存在
it based on the histogram, because the histogram indicates to me quite clearly that there is
一堆像素值小于0.45的像素，对应的是暗色的像素
a bunch of pixels with a value less then around 0.45, which are the dark ones corresponding
到后台。然后有一组明亮的像素通常大于0.45，
to the background. And then there is a set of bright pixels generally bigger then 0.45,
它包括前景或感兴趣的对象，图标和字符
which comprise the foreground or the objects of interest, the icons and the characters
在那个标志上。现在我可以选择不同的值
on that sign. Now I can choose a different value for the
阈。我可以选择，例如，我可以选择使阈值更大一些。
threshold. I can choose, for instance, I can choose to make the threshold a little bigger.
我可以选择说0.6，我可以显示新图像，我们现在看到结果
I can maybe choose say 0.6, and I can display that new image and we see now that the results
有些相似。那个标志顶部的小写字已经解体了
are somewhat similar. The small writing at the top of that sign has disintegrated and
当你更改阈值时经常发生这种情况，一些对象将开始碎片化并消失。
that often happens as you change the threshold, some objects will start to fragment and disappear.
我们可以使用工具箱，而不是以一种笨拙的试错方式做到这一点
Rather than do this in a kind of clumsy trial and error fashion, we can use the toolbox
功能ithresh。在这种情况下，我们传入了我们感兴趣的图像-和
function ithresh. We pass in the image that we are interested in —im in this case — and
我们有一个滑块。在顶部，我们看到当前阈值的指标。
what we have is a slider. Up the top we see an indicator of the current threshold value.
它默认为0.5。如果我来到这里抓住滑杆我可以提高门槛，
It defaults to 0.5. If I come down here and grab the slider bar I can increase the threshold,
现在是0.54。我可以把它做大，我可以逐步看到它，因为我提高了
now it is 0.54. I can make it bigger, and we can see that progressively as I raise the
阈。像素越来越少，其值大于阈值和结果
threshold. Fewer and fewer pixels have a value greater than the threshold and the result
越来越像是黑色的形象。同样，如果我降低阈值
is increasingly a black image. Similarly, if I reduce the threshold down
在这里说一些像0.41的东西，我们当然看到所有的字母都出现在那里
here to say something like 0.41, we certainly see that all the letters appear there quite
完全。随着我进一步降低门槛，我们将看到一些亮点
completely. As I reduce the threshold even further what we will see is some bright parts
当我们应用阈值测试并最终开始变为真实时
of the background starting to become true when we apply the threshold test and eventually
结果不是那么明确。因此，当您选择阈值时，通常会有
the result is not quite so clear cut. So when you choose a threshold there is generally
甜蜜点。太低的结果都是白色，太高，结果都是黑色的。那里
a sweet spot. Too low the result is all white, too high and the result is all black. There
在中间是个好地方。现在选择一个门槛是一件困难的事情;
is a sweet spot in the middle. Now choosing a threshold is a difficult thing;
需要一点技巧，但主要是我们应该通过直方图得知
requires a bit of skill, but primarily we should be informed by the histogram which
告诉我们一些关于灰度值如何在图像中分布的信息。和
tells us something about how the grey scale values are distributed within an image. And
我们用它来做出智能的，首选的门槛。
we use that to make an intelligent, first choice of the threshold.